And we are live. Welcome back to the
Ship Show
>> Welcome, welcome.
>> Welcome. What's up in chat? How are you
doing?
>> I I like I liked your introduction.
>> Yeah, yeah, that was that was fun.
>> [laughter]
>> Well, everything is going fine. How are
you?
>> Yes. Um busy like yeah, it's
trying to get those AI agents working by
itself, but it's not working. And I got
stuck some
revelations about something I was doing
wrong for the last
15 years. Okay, like the branch and
stuff.
>> [laughter]
>> So now everything is going to speed up
like a 10x.
>> Yeah, or at least I'm going to push more
[__] but still not going to work.
>> Well, let's see what it does.
>> Yeah, I see. But yeah, like it make more
sense at the age of AI with this like
from base workflow stuff. Yeah.
Um so yeah, like what did you do last
week?
>> Well,
I first did like 24/7 and Cloud Fable.
>> Mhm.
And then it stopped.
>> And then it stopped and I was like,
"Okay, let's touch some grass outside."
>> [laughter]
>> But I was lucky.
>> Yeah.
>> So I was pushing hard just to check
everything I have. So I was in time.
>> That's nice. And yeah, because it's
like this story is insane.
And but we're we're going to talk about
that
in a
in the next hour. Yeah, this is
the live stream. Okay, let me do the
introduction and then we go.
Cuz that's exciting. I like this mic.
Like the
standing is cool.
>> It's looking nice.
>> Yeah. I look like a radio host now.
And
welcome to the best podcast in the
world.
Uh okay.
So, you tried Claude Fable 5 for a
couple of hours until the US government
took it away from you and now you are
all sad. I know we are all like we are
sad too. Yeah, exactly.
>> [laughter]
>> And but that's not the only thing that
Anthropic brought back this week. Okay,
you all received an email about Claude
minus P like the programmatic uh common
from the your Claude subscription where
you can use it from API keys to
subscription. It's back. So, we can get
back to uh
um AFK Claude-ing, which is cool. And
we're going to talk about that in this
video too and live stream my video for
later or whatever. And uh what's the
conclusion? The conclusion of my
introduction I forgot.
>> Yeah, we need Fable back.
>> Yeah. Oh yeah, we need Fable back. Watch
this video. Thank you. Subscribe.
>> Yes.
>> Uh okay.
>> So, first of all, when are we going to
see people who post online?
Uh I'm looking for a husband from
outside the US and my benefit is I can
give you Claude Fable.
>> Yeah, that's that's good. Bro, that's
good. Like that's the next Tinder.
>> Yeah.
>> [laughter]
>> You need to pay a lot but you get Claude
Fable included.
>> But wait
>> [laughter]
>> wait like the they said
Fable 5 will be only available to
Americans?
>> Yeah, only to US residents. So, outside
the US nobody can use it.
So, even the people who work at uh
Anthropic
>> Yeah.
>> who are not in the US, they can't use
it, their own stuff.
>> Uh that's that's
Okay, so
that's the tweet from Claude Dev, but we
have the other one after. Uh as a result
of the uh US government directive, we
are suspending access to Claude Fable 5
for all users. You can continue uh to
use all of the other Claude models. Um
across Claude product, new session will
run on your selected default model or
Office 4.8.
And the official tweet was the uh US
government sitting national security
authorities has issued
an export control directive to suspend
all access to Fable 5 and Metis 5 by any
foreign national.
A foreign national means like
aliens or people inside the US.
I even I
I Chinese from China in China land can't
access
>> Yeah, yeah, exactly. You have to be a US
citizen to be able to access it. So, and
it doesn't matter if you're not, but
you're inside the US, you cannot access
Claude Fable.
>> That's crazy.
>> So, it doesn't matter if you're inside
or outside the United States.
>> Yeah.
Like
>> And then the bottom line says is in said
it including foreign national Anthropic
employees. So, everybody non-US
even if they are in the main office in
the United States, they cannot use
Claude Fable.
How are you going to do that?
>> I don't
I mean KYC? I mean you were coming for
crypto, right? So, there is that.
>> Yeah, yeah. So, it is like I'm going to
the toilet, I didn't lock my PC, anybody
can use it now.
>> Yeah. Yeah, yeah, it's not like
I mean, yeah, like Anthropic will be the
new Binance.
Yeah, it's going to be fun.
>> And uh okay, we got a message from
Praka.
Sorry if I don't say your name
correctly. Uh why do connect webinar
with no identities? It's because we're
we're just getting started, man. And we
are recording a video at the same time.
So, it's not a video webinar. It's more
like a live stream.
So, welcome home.
>> [laughter]
>> Happy to have you here.
>> Yes. Um okay, so the next effect of this
order is that we must abruptly disable
Fable 5 and Metis 5 for all customers to
ensure compliance. Do you think they
will bring them back
this week?
>> The Fable 5?
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah, well, the last thing I read is
that they were trying to but didn't
have any success, so
I don't know how many options they have
and how easy it is.
>> I mean,
it's
you can already like see some benchmark
that it was already distilling some
Chinese model anyway, so
>> Yeah, but
I think they are just too scared that
other people abuse it.
That's the main issue, right?
>> [snorts]
>> Yes.
>> yeah.
>> But I mean,
I is that some like people in Washington
saying, "Oh yeah, no like
Anthropic told me what to eat tonight,
so we can't use it nationwide?"
>> Well, as I understood it,
Amazon people found out that was
possible to jailbreak it or that it was
already jailbroken and they reported it
to the US government.
And then the US government decided to
just block it for everybody.
>> But like the US government doesn't have
access to the model before anyone else?
>> Yeah, of course they do. I think they
have to and they have been announcing it
a long time. So, everybody knew about
Metis. They were actually already
testing it, giving it to bigger
companies and the government is always
included.
>> Exactly. Yeah, so even like the timing
is well because you launch it then you
said in 3 days going to be API keys and
then in 2 days after boom you like US
government say no no no.
>> Yeah, but did you see any difference
between Opus and Fable?
Because you used it, right?
>> Uh so yes, I used it and I just saw my
subscription like going for 15 months.
Um
but I preferred
4.8 plus ultra code
than Fable 5.
>> And for coding or for reviews or you
didn't do any different testing?
>> I was doing like more um
yeah, coding task because yeah I was
busy on that that stuff but like yeah,
instead of like doing some
asset generation like from the replicate
things that
Opus could have done that already.
We should have rebuilt the games
directly because I saw some crazy game
setup um
on on the timeline with Fable 5.
Uh
>> Do you still have it?
>> 5
Fable 5 games.
Be careful what I'm sharing live.
Uh
>> It should be a blank account.
>> So up.
Yeah.
But wait, no that's not possible and
that's not Fable because
that can't generate asset. Oh yeah,
whatever like the capability were like
way more than anything else, right?
I mean of course jeez.
Trading Yeah, so if you are able to vibe
code that kind of game, I don't think
it's
I don't think it's real.
Is it?
A world of Cloudcraft. Oh, okay.
Damn.
Yeah, that's not just Fable.
>> No, no. People just use Fable to get
into the trending topics, but they are
using a lot more or they have an
existing code base, existing images, and
graphics.
>> Yeah, it was not launched with Fable
yet. So
>> Don't believe everything you see on X.
>> Yeah, true that.
But wait, like is a project like 6-day
old?
Okay.
So maybe this is real. I don't know.
Uh
Cloudcraft. That's That's kind of
interesting though.
>> And he has how many stars?
>> 800 and
200 fork.
But yeah, the first commit.
Right.
Okay, June 16.
No, I won't.
I want that and I want that.
Okay. Maybe that was a
Fable 5 stuff there.
>> Yeah, but still.
I think he had some stuff before
available.
>> Uh
When was the launch? Oh yeah, that's
That's going to be
>> I think a week ago.
>> Uh
thank
thank.
13.
Okay, I'm not going to do that, but uh
3 days
>> Yeah, just take 7 and 8 of June, then
you know.
>> Okay.
>> [clears throat]
>> If any of you have a flavor of my
current first time
Simcoe
Who's the author? Yeah.
Closed. Committed last week. No, they
started with it. No.
>> [snorts]
>> That's interesting.
Sorry, whatever.
Yeah. So, what did you What did you do
with Fable? Like when we while
we had it.
>> I had it
check every code base I have for every
project and write down an MD file with
all the bugs, all the issues, all the
security issues, everything it found.
I didn't have it completely fix
everything
because that was taking too much tokens.
>> That was That was crazy.
>> Yes. So, I upgraded to the max 20X and I
just had every project that a customer
pays me to maintain. I had it fully
analyze everything.
So, right now I have a full backlog
of all the projects with like some
projects have having 20 MD files in full
setup doing everything from a pen test
to a to a security to to small I don't
know what everything I asked.
And now I can just
use Codex and and Opus to fix everything
even when we don't have Fable.
>> So, would you use Fable as an
orchestrator or like finding features,
stuff to do, and then execute it with
like 4.8 or XI?
>> Yeah, it depends. If I have to look at
the
cost for the tokens and credits,
uh I would have it just double-check
everything. So, I would create a full
plan
uh on Codex
and have Fable check it, give feedback,
and then have Codex build everything,
and then have Fable do the full review.
>> Okay, so you would rather like have
the executor like the executioner like
the the coder uh Fable 5 and you plan
before with all the cheapest model.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay.
>> Because if Fable can actually add
everything in the documentation, you
don't need an expensive model to build
everything because the thinking is done
up front.
>> Yeah, but like if the plan is first and
you have the cheapest model, then you
probably going to miss something in the
plan, no?
>> Yeah, but that's what the what Fable is
going to fix, I hope. He's going to
check the plan as well and document
everything
even better. [clears throat]
>> Okay. Okay, so first pass with like a
cheapest model, then the expensive one,
then you execute with
the cheapest one XI XI or
4.8, whatever, and then Okay, makes
sense.
>> I wasn't able to do a full check on
quality yet to to see the difference,
but I did a test where I asked Fable to
do the full full planning and where I
did Codex with a with a Fable check.
And both of the plans are like fully
documented. I didn't have them build
both, but
uh
if you have Fable planning everything
from the start from scratch, it is way
more expensive.
>> Yeah. Yeah, no, no, it's crazy. And even
like a plan with like 4.8 ultra code,
uh I have session that just like it I
have one session it was like just to
review and refactor like the a search
bar
to
to make it like the same UI the same
component and same stuff because it did
like the same features five times like
five times and five different ways. So,
I wanted to refactor that into one
component. The plan was like 15 minutes.
>> Yeah.
I know it it looks like it checks
everything and it goes really deep into
the code to see if it can find any
relations or
or whatever, but
a week ago, more than a week ago, we
were really happy with Codex 5.5.
>> Yeah. I and now I can't use it anymore.
Like even for the for the talking point
of like Okay, so it's not recording.
It's like more writing stuff. Like I
should use another model for that even.
>> Yeah.
>> But um
it it was dumb. Like and now I feel like
5.5 missed so it's I
missed so many things.
Yeah. So, yeah. It's it's kind of crazy.
And
um so, like now you are full on 4.8
Ultra Guard?
>> Uh yeah, combined with
Codex 5.5 XHigh.
>> Okay. Okay. Okay. And like with a skill,
do you send the plan to a VR skill or do
you still copy-paste?
>> No. No. No. I have my own skill that I
use.
>> Nice.
Always.
>> Not copy-pasting anymore.
>> Yeah. No.
It's so 2024.
>> Yeah.
>> [laughter]
>> Uh yeah, that's nice. Um
so, yeah. Do you think like the US
government will put it back? 5.5? And
they will say okay, uh that was allowed.
Well, sorry.
>> You know see see you know see both
coming online. I know it's expensive for
people having those um
like a full server at home, a 128 GB RAM
PC.
That's not even a PC anymore, but
>> [laughter]
>> and they are using open source models.
I think if those go harder,
then
um Anthropic needs the bigger models.
like Fable, because otherwise people are
going to skip
Anthropic and use different solutions.
>> I mean, yeah, like
I don't know, like I don't know where
we're going with those open-source
models because Okay, so coding it's an
interesting
crowd of user and pro user because we
are nerds and tech guys, so we can
[__] install a rack at home just
because it's cool, right? And then you
use you use
a couple of like computers to have your
own model at home, but like in term of
adoption and distribution, you're not
going to It's mass
uh critical mass with that because it's
too niche and it's like the skill set to
do that even if you are like AI guided.
I don't know how many people will
install their own open-source model, but
everyone will download ChatGPT.
>> Yeah, but what does a PC cost with that
much of of gigabytes of RAM? Like 4 to
5K? I've seen them.
>> That's a lot.
>> Well, it isn't for a company.
>> Yeah, yeah, I know.
>> You just hire an IT guy that puts it in
their own server room, sets it up,
points all the API points locally to
their internal VPN network as well, so
you can do it from outside, and you're
done.
>> Yeah.
And then you hire one guy just to
monitor that so you don't have like uh
>> Yeah.
>> I have
>> Because if you make like 5K in in
tokens,
that's easy.
>> Oh, yeah. I Yeah.
Um with my 200 subscription, I'm like
with Fable, I was burning I I don't like
I topped at 2.5 billion token in a day.
>> Yeah. Now,
calculate how much money that is. That's
insane.
>> Yeah, I was at one uh 1K 1.5K a day.
So, yeah. And about those local source
models, like it's the Alex thing come
back because he preached that for yes uh
for 6 months.
5 months ago I bought 30k of Mac Studios
Mac Mini and the JX box. I did this
because I predicted the hardware price
would explode government will start
limiting LLM usage local models would
get way more powerful. AI influencers
touched me for this. Call me
called me a dangerous hype merchant.
Literally 100% of those prediction came
true. Mac Studio above 100 gigabyte are
not even sold anymore.
Really?
>> Yeah, Apple took them away from the
website but
you have like AMD has another solution
right now.
>> Yes.
>> Yeah.
February 5th got banned and new local
models are Opus level. Are they?
>> And people say they are.
>> Yeah.
>> I didn't test it myself yet.
>> Yeah. Yeah, because you yeah, because
you need to spend like
3 days to implement it but then you have
a full dashboard of features to
implement too. So
>> Yeah, I'd rather wait for some
benchmarks because if I spend like 5K
and 3 days for setting everything up.
>> Yeah, exactly.
>> And then it feels like Opus 4.2 that
would be bad.
>> True.
Another sample message out waiting local
model of the future. Yeah, okay, cool.
And what you were talking about was the
AMD
Is that the arrow?
>> AMD
Oh, that one.
>> So that by the way that's not even true
100% like the price
would be way more expensive than 1.5k
but uh
Anyway, that's
>> Yeah, I've seen seen people put it into
a PC and then
I think it cost like 4 or 5K.
>> Yeah.
Okay, let's watch this quickly.
>> Now, I would say this is pretty
beautiful.
Do Do guys agree?
>> Yes.
>> [applause]
>> So, let me tell you what it is. This is
the smallest AI development system in
the world.
Capable of running models with up to 200
billion parameters locally. Not
connected to anything.
It's powered by our highest end Ryzen AI
Max processor with 128 GB of high-speed
unified memory that is shared by CPU,
GPU, and NPU.
This architecture accelerates system
performance and makes it possible to
efficiently run large AI models on a
compact desktop PC that fits in your
hand.
Thank you.
>> [applause]
>> Yeah. So,
are we going to have AI models directly
in our MacBook Pro?
And then uh
we don't need a subscription anymore?
>> I'm spending like $500 at least every
month on AI subscriptions. If I can
replace it by spending 5K on this,
I don't mind.
>> Yeah, no, for sure.
>> But
how do you upgrade that?
>> You
buy a second one.
>> [laughter]
>> Yeah.
Because the yeah, the problem with the
hardware is like instead of like a brew
install
uh code and codex to get the stable 10,
uh do I need to buy another one that can
Oh, you can upgrade the software inside
the hardware, right? But uh
then the power the the params
uh needs to fit in?
>> Yeah.
Well,
I'm waiting for the other people to try
it first.
>> Yeah, exactly.
>> The real tech guys who are like tech
savvy and they they even buy one, take
it apart, and they say it's not good
enough, and they put in their own parts.
Let those people test first.
>> [laughter]
>> I mean
Yeah. For what we do like
uh uh Opus 4.8 and Codex 5.5 / 5.6
incoming whatever, that's good enough
with like we don't need to get to those
uh
crazy leftovers point on benchmark to do
one more integration in on Reactor PHP
whatever.
>> We are not working for banks or the
government or whatever. So, we are
building normal systems with uh where
the security that we add is good enough.
>> Yeah, not exactly.
>> We don't need like triple uh
authentication and I know whatever they
are adding.
>> For sure. And okay, so what also
um
getting hype on X right now, it's all
about loop coding stuff and thanks to
Matt Pocock is the kind of like the
leader of that trend because he builds
like his skills
for engineers uh
AI arrow deck.
Can I access the website directly?
Uh
learn pro
agent skills for
Okay.
>> We have someone who is buying an RTX Pro
6000.
Any comments?
>> Yeah.
Oh.
Oh. Uh okay. So,
my uh hi Brian. Uh my friend is getting
Static to buy an RTX Pro 6000
and 96 GB PC for AI and some other work.
Should he wait for this stuff?
I mean Static.
I know.
>> The biggest issue is every It's like the
AI models. People now know that the uh
if you are the first on market with a
big
uh update on the RAM
then you can sell it so much and that's
what they are doing doing. They have a
speed race. So, I I right now they are
coming with different and better models
like every one or two months.
>> Yeah.
>> Um
but if you're spending this amount of
money,
you better calculate the return on
investment properly
because if it only saves you $200 a
month, it's a lot to to to pay. But if
you can hook up like um
customers that you have who are using
your setup as well via an API connection
and they don't buy additional tokens,
you can invoice them for the usage, then
it's a perfect setup.
>> Yeah, exactly. And no matter what the
price, that that business model works
for everything you do.
>> Yeah.
>> Like if you have customers to pay twice
the price you buy something,
that's good.
>> Yeah.
But
>> Oh, yeah.
>> I would do a proper calculation on uh
the new models and this model.
And even if they say it is really cheap
and it does the same thing, it's good to
to to make sure that you double-check
everything because it's a lot of money.
>> Yeah.
That's for sure.
And that's my comment to the input.
Thanks, Michelle.
Uh [snorts] okay, so
Yes, I have his back.
Is we put the story. Do you Do you know
this guy? Do you use this SQL?
>> I have seen him, but I haven't used SQL
yet.
>> Yeah.
So, okay, better than that.
I have for the SQL, yes, that's
So, here are my seven phases of AI
product development. I've been thinking
that the pre-PRD phase need more
structure. You need to figure out of the
shape of the design three first before
then working down higher fidelity
prototypes. In other words, grill grill
with dogs needs to change again. Okay,
whatever.
Uh so,
grill, research prototype, PRD issues,
implementation review.
Um
is that in this order? Yes.
And that's all working on GitHub. So
basically it's building software on
GitHub actions.
>> That's cool. Yeah.
>> Like okay so yeah I have some kind of ID
for an app okay so you
but it's basically ask
the the tool
ask user about blah blah blah you know
when you
reverse prompt today I
was with like a
the AI asking a question to have more
details about it. Researcher research
if execution would involve difficult
explore phase create a research MD asset
to catch them so you can explore like
different opportunities like for example
for you can research on
Google on GitHub open source open source
project if that's like something that
already exists that your app idea or
features or whatever and then you can
either import it or just don't do it and
do something else whatever.
Prototype hash how to add in code to get
early feedback. PRD create a markdown
file to describe the destination visual
story and implementation notes. Issues
turn the PRD into individual tickets.
Implement in a loop run a coding agent
to execute all of the tickets on the
Kanban board.
That I think 4.8 can do it with ultra
code.
>> Yeah and
I am really sure that both of us did
this setup before but just more
manually.
>> Yeah.
>> Because it wasn't able to do everything
itself but
exactly this flow and maybe even some
improvements because of course we we
have tried a lot and the small tweaks do
a lot but we have been doing this
before.
>> Yeah.
Yeah but like the fact that it's all a
skill and what I like also it's like
it's it's running on GitHub actions.
>> Yeah but those get expensive.
>> Yes. Uh except if you run open source
software, but like uh
I mean, I think it Yeah, I
I think it's run on GitHub Actions
because it Yeah, I know. I know. It It
is because I So, what I did was like I
took his skills repository and I compare
it with like the ship ship dev / skills
that we have.
And I asked
I asked Claude, "Yeah, can we merge some
skills? Is there any duplicate? Is it
matching my current workflow?" Blah blah
blah. And yeah, and he asked me for an
entropy entropy key. So,
uh it's run on GitHub Action when like
you tag
when you add the label to
uh on the issue or if you move the issue
to a uh
a column on the Kanban board, then the
agent pick it up automatically.
I mean, with the GitHub Action. So, you
can either use an automation uh on the
Codex app or
Claude app with a routine to pick up new
tasks that have been ready for your
agent to do.
>> Mhm. [clears throat]
>> But that's what they do in a loop, like
the implementation phase in a loop,
um to build software
with AI.
>> Yeah. Well,
I still prefer having my own setup on my
Mac mini and I don't mean like open claw
or paper clip or whatever.
>> Yeah.
>> Just have Claude build
the GitHub Actions in your own Python
script, run it locally on your Mac mini
in your own network, and use that to
automate. It will save you a lot of
money.
>> Mhm.
>> And you can just add additional checks
and and loops on whatever you want and
you don't rely on GitHub.
>> Yeah.
>> I mean, I I like GitHub as a central
place of everything.
Like like to have all of the issues can
be bold and even like the road map
stuff. I think I'm going to like migrate
like the GenFit deployment development
directly on
on GitHub side with that kind of
workflow because that's basically open
source now. And something for ship code,
I kind of like that aspect of it cuz
again like I can run like all of the
end-to-end test.
>> Yeah, the problem is I'm going to have
[__] burn my subscription.
>> Yeah.
And I'm still convinced that I don't
want to rely on external services where
I cannot control the final price.
I think Microsoft 365 it's it's totally
different but it showed this.
Everybody bought Word and Office before
>> Yeah.
>> for like $200 per user
and you could use it for as long as you
want but you didn't go to the next
version you had to buy it again. And now
everybody's using the Microsoft 365.
And
in July they are raising the prices
between 10 to 16% again.
And if your
full company is relying on it, you don't
have a choice but a 16% increase is a
lot.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah, but I mean
If you vendor locked in, you're vendor
locked in, right? Like
>> Yeah, so now you can just build whatever
you want with AI.
>> Mhm.
>> Why are you going to rely on GitHub
actions?
>> Because of like the automation CI. Like
I have the quad rail on GitHub.
>> Yeah, but you can just build anything
you want within one or two days.
>> I'm not I don't think I can write code
GitHub.
>> Not full GitHub.
>> [laughter]
>> Like yeah yeah I mean and also like in
term of computer power like I would need
to
to run a GitHub action. I mean, I would
kind of do it for Victor anyway, but
like we have No, we have like our own
GCP instance to run the CI because I
didn't want to pay for GitHub action
because yeah, we ran out of the 5K uh
minutes like in 2 days.
>> Yeah.
>> And
so
and like one day after we upgraded like
the to enterprise because
uh on the GCP like the instance was
already not enough.
>> Yeah.
>> Because it's like permanent like not
permanent, but like we do like five
release a day or every hour.
And uh
that's take a lot of compute and
processor time. So,
the problem.
>> Yeah, that would be expensive.
>> Yeah. Yeah. I think like Peter saying
talking about
Open Claw, he said
it would cost me like 15 grand a month
to run it because um all I mean,
I didn't
specify
for GitHub action or checks, but uh
probably like AI cost anyway, too. But
yeah, that was part of it because he's
permanently testing everything all the
time.
>> Yeah. Where does he get the time?
>> I mean, it
You have 24 hours, but you have
unlimited token at OpenAI. So,
>> He's spending money.
>> I mean, on months.
>> [laughter]
>> Yeah.
>> And now like Open Claw is behind Hermes
agent. So, that's something else.
Like Yeah, I don't know, man. It's well.
But like Okay, so you're not convinced
by Matt's uh we already doing it anyway,
right?
>> Yeah, we already doing it, but maybe
slightly different.
>> Yeah.
>> And I feel like every one or 2 weeks,
they found out something new that's way
better and all the rest is [__]
And yeah, I don't know.
>> I mean, like
>> It feels like they want to be on the
timeline. That's it.
>> Yeah, true. Yeah, also that Yeah, also
that. That's that's also a part of that
when you read something on Twitter,
that's a possibility that the goal is
just to
make some impression and get some
fame or slash earn money.
>> Yeah, I think those those IT guys who
are in the attic only working with no
light at all.
>> Yeah.
>> [laughter]
>> Those are the guys that have like the
best setup.
>> Mhm.
>> They are automating everything.
And so even when they go outside for a
full week, everything just keeps on
running.
>> Yeah.
But then you spend like [__] ton of
money on to get Like if I start to to
So,
last week I played on automation because
I wanted to have some time off, but
still uh shipping some features.
I On Monday, I was like on my 5 hours
session limits and it was 7:00 a.m.
Monday.
>> Yeah.
>> So, that's a problem.
>> Yeah, yeah, that's a problem.
>> And also yeah, that was also during the
couple of days when we had fever. I had
one day fever like
nuke.
>> Yeah.
>> That's the day I had I bought a second
second subscription.
But yeah.
Like
it [snorts] yeah. So, okay, we're not
that far from this. But like
from seven steps,
>> Mhm.
>> uh six of them are PM management, like
project manager and stuff like that.
Like real research prototype PRD Yeah,
prototype could be
hybrid, but PRD issues.
PM.
How long do you spend per PRD slash
to build the plan and to make sure like
everything is
covered.
>> I don't know, it varies a lot.
It is between like 10 minutes to 2 hours
or 3 hours.
>> Okay, [__]
>> But that my goal is always then to one
shot it.
>> Yeah. And like do you succeed?
>> Yes.
Well, I don't. Cloud does.
>> [laughter]
>> Opus succeeds, but
>> Yeah.
And okay, so you if you have a PRD for
that do you schedule for three like
prepare for 3 hours?
How long does it take for Opus or like
Codex whatever to do it?
>> Yeah, yeah, it well, eventually it takes
him like 3 hours, but sometimes I ask
hey, come with three different solutions
and I ask Codex to do the exact same
thing to come with three different
solutions and I just merge them into one
document and then say what's the
difference,
uh what can you take from other
solutions to improve it. So and then
they think like 10 minutes again. So the
3 hours is including the thinking time
of the AI.
>> Mhm.
Damn. And do you ask Claude to give you
like directive or directions?
Or better solution?
>> Yeah, always.
>> Yeah.
I mean like do you offer solution and
then Claude is giving you a better one?
>> Uh yeah, it does because so I still
Google it sometimes.
>> Damn.
>> Yeah, yeah. Because
uh
my question in the beginning was why
didn't you think about this or what is
this solution that somebody else used? I
don't even do it on Google. Even in X
you can Google it and other devs are
sharing solutions.
Um
And the questions like why are they
using this one? What are the benefits
that they have and how does that compare
to the benefits that I have from a
solution that you created for me? Those
questions make huge improvements on the
eventual solutions that I'm adding.
>> Yeah.
>> Because I think like even an AI has
tunnel vision. It goes into a certain
way and it just keeps on building on the
steps that it has already taken.
>> Yeah. Yeah, but that's why you have also
hallucination when like it just get a
tiny bit of hallucination from one
feature or one direction or one text tag
that you had
like couple of weeks ago, but like the
module doesn't exist anymore in the code
base and they're like
it's going to reinstall all of the
package and you are going back to you
are going back to that that pipe that
was just you know what? That's why also
like
if you have in your cloud MD don't do
that
it will think about that
like the stuff that you didn't specify
and it will do it anyway.
>> Yeah.
So, yeah.
>> But that's also why I like to do and to
have cloud and codex both think about
the same thing and you will see that
they find the entire different solutions
and when you give the solution to the
other one it says hey this is
interesting.
>> Yeah.
Yeah, no, no, no,
yeah, oh yeah, that's one yeah, because
it's built differently and so it think
differently.
>> They even come with different solutions
or different software usage.
And then when you say so if I have a
small addition like I already have
stripe fully integrated that's easy
because I just add a different function,
but when I need to include software or
whatever I want to do a full research
and that takes time.
>> Mhm. That makes sense.
>> And the question always is I want to
scale to an enterprise solution.
>> But wait, what? What do you mean?
>> I always say I want to scale to an
enterprise solution so make sure that
whatever you build is scalable.
>> Yeah, that's a dangerous proof though
because you're going to
It's going to install you like a full
rack and stuff.
>> [laughter]
>> No, no, no.
No, no, no.
It is, yeah. And they say that it does
the the first part, but
>> Yeah.
>> you don't want it to build something and
when you scale to 10 you 10 users using
it that it crashes because the RAM is
going too hard or the I don't know
whatever the issue can be, but
>> Yeah.
True that. Uh hi Michael, what's up?
Good afternoon from Europe. I don't know
where you are.
>> Yes.
>> Thanks for coming back.
Uh okay, so Matt Pocock skills
we are using them. We thought using
them, but that's that's okay. That's
cool.
Uh
yeah, Boris Cheney I can't get the
loop interview for the Cloud Code Guy.
Oh, now we have it. Nice.
Thanks a lot for
fixing with
>> making this possible.
>> Yeah.
Uh
tag path
Let's go. Okay.
So
yeah, Kratos Cloud Code
Uh 100% of your all for pull requests
that are in tropical run by Cloud Code.
80 to 90% of code review, too. It shows
a bit because that's not the best user
experience /
code quality you can get.
And yeah, that was the whole loop
engineering thesis that was based on
this interview. That was um
like from him and then all everywhere on
the timeline you have uh
people explaining how loops works.
>> It's easy, yeah?
>> Yeah.
>> Do check React.
>> [laughter]
>> Uh
so yeah, what a loop actually does.
Yeah, let's go. Find work, any Twitter
agent, check results, record what
happened, decide next move. Yeah. Okay,
thank you.
That's a good bro.
Do you do QA with like Playwright or any
like similar [snorts] tools to
do the QA?
>> I didn't. Should I?
>> What?
>> Should I do it?
>> Ah, man. No, but
but okay, okay, wait, wait, wait.
All right, let's go back to yeah, that.
If
AI ship pull request faster than you in
in your last 20 20 years. How do you QA
that amount of pull request if you're
not doing it with AI?
>> Yeah, I probably do it like a noob.
>> [laughter]
>> Uh, you you you test everything
manually?
>> Uh, a lot.
>> Yeah. I I yeah.
>> But it also writes testing, so
>> Yeah.
>> I have tests on everything, but
it feels like I have like an infinite
amount of tests.
>> Yeah.
>> And I even needed to add rules for
testing because if it tries redeploying
your database, that's not good.
>> Yeah, like the migration stuff. Yeah,
like yeah, [__] off. Yeah.
>> That deletes the entire database in your
test.
>> Yeah, like in my CI I ask you take a
snapshot before every migration.
There is a backup like every migration
in the CI like yeah.
Um, but
yeah, it's
I think also like different state of the
code base, it's kind of different. Like
if you start a project then everything
is broken at the same time and you need
to fix, that's harder to ship fast. But
once you have something strong, then you
can reduce the surface of the pull
request and then uh, it's way more main-
maintainable and manageable, I guess I
would say.
>> Yeah. But do you make like big
uh, changes or do you just split
everything in
many small tasks?
>> Like this week I did a task where
I I changed the plugin from to to the
form validation. So, that needs to be a
wild surface like architecture choice,
blah blah blah.
But I won't because I want the same
tools and it was like from Yub to just
end library or stuff like that. Uh that
I need to go into
>> Yeah, that's a big one.
>> Yeah. But I want to reduce my the
surface of my pull request, but I don't
have like a product is not stable
enough.
>> Mhm.
>> But we're getting there, but
it's a little bit time.
Couple of days.
>> And you don't do like two versions in
your code? Like have 90% of the forms on
the old one and only 10% on new one, so
you can easily test and make sure it
works.
>> No no no no. I I don't like legacy code
stuff. Especially with the AI. Like if
you do something, you do it everywhere
because uh
Like I I don't want to have like one
form with one plugin and then another
form with another one.
Maybe I'm wrong, but I would rather like
nah.
Yeah, I don't think I'm wrong.
>> I always get a bit scared when
I have a service
full system for a customer and I need to
update something big like this.
The first thing I do is add it like a
V2.
Put it on the forms that are not used
that much, so that we can probably check
and manage it for two or three days. See
how many errors we get and when it's all
working.
>> Yeah.
>> That feels to me like
>> Yeah, because you already have like
customers on production and stuff. Like
I
like the apps I work on are more like
greener, so
Again, it's different. Like yeah.
>> Yes. So, it it depends on how your setup
is and usage.
>> Yeah. I don't want to change this phone
plug-in whatsoever anytime soon because
now it's done, but
and I mean it also match the tools that
I have so then I can go faster.
>> Mhm.
>> [clears throat]
>> Uh so, yeah.
Uh
I mean
I forgot to share.
>> Yeah, we were in the loops.
>> Yeah.
Uh loop engineering is replacing
yourself as the prompter.
I don't know if I Yeah, okay. So,
primitive automation discovery triage
job in the loop discovery and triage on
schedule, code acts up automation tab,
uh cloud code schedule task and cron
loop call hooks, GitHub action.
Uh there is like the routines in the
cloud code apps, too.
Work tree work tree isolate isolate
parallel features by chain work tree per
thread, Git work tree work tree
isolation. Yeah, okay. So, I mean work
tree scales, plug-in connectors connect
your tools, MCP MCP server. Okay, that's
basically the same thing.
Uh sub agents, which is managed by 4.8
and then track code. So, yeah, don't
care about that. I mean, yeah, like the
sub agent was something that you we
define like in 24, right?
Do you still use them? Do you still have
sub agents?
>> Yeah.
>> No, anymore. Isn't it replaced by
skills?
Probably and like the the current Opus
4.8 Fable did it really good. You just
gave it a task and it creates the agents
himself.
>> Yeah, so it's like having an agent.
Yeah, so if you have an agent Yeah,
okay. So, maybe we should reuse again
sub agent because Fable will come back
Yeah, at some point.
>> Well, I had Fable like asking him one
thing and he deployed 231 agents.
>> Yeah,
yeah, like I showed you, right? Like it
it worked for 20 30 minutes and I had
like 85 agent or something.
>> I don't know, man.
>> And like
almost 10 million amount of tokens used.
>> I can't wait to have like a a proper
framework that's telling me, "Okay, this
is what you do. You do that. You follow
the rules, and now you can build your
software." And that's it. That's it. Not
like having skills and sub agent and
plugin connector. Please, simplify.
Um because yeah, we we still need the
quad rails and stuff that we can find
from a framework. So, do we have a AI
Is that Vercel AI SDK? No, not even.
Uh but uh
Yeah. Yeah, everyone is still trying to
figure out anyway, I I would say.
Uh run the four conditions.
Test before you do anything. Is that
TDD?
The task repeats. Verification is
automated. Token budget up some the
waste. Agent has senior agent in our
tools.
Answer yes to all four pass builder
loop. What?
Run the four condition loops and a cost
under four conditions. Miss one and the
loop cost more than it returned. The
honest take for alpha signal analysis
and the part and the part most egg
threat skip. Uh okay, okay.
Um
uh the task repeats. A loop amortizes
its setup across many runs.
For one job, a good prompt is faster and
cheaper if the work does not recur
weekly.
You don't have a loop. You have a script
you run once. Fair enough.
Verification is automated. The loop
needs something that can fill the work
without you in the room. A test suite, a
type checker, linter, a build.
Your token budget can accept the waste.
Loop reread context, retry, explore.
That burns token whether or not the run
ships anything.
The technique scales with budget, which
is why it reads as obvious to people
with effective free token and reckless
to people. Yeah.
Yeah.
That That's the problem. Like we are not
Peter Peter with like working at Codex
with like unlimited subscription. That's
the main problem. Like the budget
behind those loop
nuts.
>> Maybe that's why it's it it is their own
people who are constantly giving us
these options.
>> Yeah.
>> Like the Ralph loop and now this loop.
I mean
yeah.
There is
in a way there is some
good ideas of
behind it because it makes sense, right?
Like
you you set up like the scope of the
issue and then you had your test and
then till all of the test is passed
passed then you have your loop and
that's it and then the task is not done.
But like
Ultra code does that by itself.
>> Yeah, it does. And you don't have any
influence on it. It just keeps on going
and when you think I ask a small
question it goes on for 20 minutes.
>> Yeah.
>> I think there can be an issue here
because if you actually pay for all the
tokens and you have an infinite loop
that cannot fix itself.
>> Yeah. Like
>> I would only not real for after three
runs and you still haven't fixed it.
Stop it, flag it, give me a push
message.
>> Yeah.
Yeah, because like Ultra code on loop
you going to do that twice.
>> Yeah.
>> Um who wins, who lost? Who wins, who
loses? A loop's favor whoever can spend.
Okay. Yeah.
Uh actually who actually benefit in
practice? Team with repetitive machine
checkable work and a budget to run it.
Code base with strong existing test
suites.
I think I think first teams with
multiple agent pattern already in use.
Uh who should skip it today? Solo
builders and
on consumer plan. Let's go.
Anyone working on code with no automated
verification and teams whose real
constraint is review capacity rather
than typing speed.
Um
Oh
Sup A Jira. Is it better to get uh
AI coding program running locally?
Uh where
as a
local model or running locally from
subscription instead of GitHub or
>> Yeah, if you can use it in your
subscription, then it's harder to
automate and and build a loop because it
will stop every time. Building the loop
uses always AI credits.
>> Yeah. I mean like if you I with your
track code mod, uh
it will work for like 20 1 hour
whatever, and then you can check if the
task is done. And then you you Yeah,
it's like you need to be prompted and
say, "Oh yeah, try again. That's
broken." But at least
you can QA during the loop.
>> Yeah. But still solo builders and
consumers,
they never have a full system that needs
to be built that is as big as this one.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. So they always have smaller tasks.
So the loop is just overkill, I think.
>> But I mean you are solo builder and you
have
uh
>> Yeah, but I never needed to code for
like
hours at once. That's insane.
>> Uh
>> Cuz
>> I just say you prep for 3 hours and then
the agent runs 3 hours.
>> Well, I prep for 3 hours and hoping the
agent can do it in 30 minutes.
>> [laughter]
>> Because I did a lot preparations, but I
I the preparations like step-by-step.
>> Yeah.
>> And even if I do like a full system
build, like I I say I want full Zendesk.
>> Mhm.
>> I have it I am doing like a full day of
planning, researching, checking, but I
divide it into steps and I just build
step-by-step. I never have it built like
step one until 50.
>> Yeah. Yeah, build a build Zendesk, make
no mistakes. That's that doesn't work.
>> That's insane.
>> Yeah.
>> And I I I really want to make sure that
every step that we have that has one
functionality, I test it after it's
done.
>> Yeah.
Oh, that makes sense.
Uh oh, yeah. Okay, so local models so
you can skip paying credits. Yes, okay.
So
you would have
I mean, that's what we already talked
about like a couple of weeks ago like
about those open clue and RMS
um orchestrator where you plan with the
paid model and then you execute with
like open open open source model
on your local machine so you don't
spend that credit and you only pay for
plans.
>> Yeah. And if you want to do it with a
competiting of a competitor model right
now, it's really expensive. You need
that the PC that we just showed the AMD
like 4 to 5K, have the knowledge how to
set it up and you can't run it fully
locally.
>> Yeah.
>> But if you have a big project, that
could that could be like
>> Mhm.
>> a good investment.
>> Yeah.
That makes sense. And
yeah, but the problem also with the
local models
right now like
uh
Quen's 3.7
uh I don't think you can run that on a
Raspberry Pi.
>> No, no.
No, you need like a bigger PC.
>> Yeah.
Uh 3.7
uh
requirements.
Uh,
when
3.7 series by Alibaba consists probably
sequence whatever whatever complex
reasoning local hardware is not required
instead you can access the API. Yeah,
okay.
Architecture 1 billion token access
method.
Yeah, self hosting.
>> 50 cent per million token.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Uh, self hosting
VRAM 24
to 48 depending of quantization
and the target model environment python.
Yeah, okay, whatever. Uh,
can I run it on
uh, M1 Mac.
Yes, okay.
For M with 16 gigabyte RAM.
Uh, what you can smaller models, okay, 7
to 9 billion.
Mac with 32 RAM M1
Pro Max Ultra. That's not bad.
It's worth a try.
Yeah.
Ollama, yeah, okay. So, that's the whole
setup but uh,
Okay, so you know what? I have a good
laptop I think. Yeah, okay, so
try it and come back next week and then
tell us how it goes.
>> Yes, we are next week here at the same
time.
>> Yes.
That would be that would be interesting.
Um,
yeah.
[__] we're going back to open flow LMS
orchestration. I mean, do you see a
future with that? Like
Yeah, I do you think you're going to
code with like five agents and one
orchestrator and like five of them.
>> I prefer building my own orchestrator
because every time I updated one of
those, I was having issues.
>> True.
That's why Ship got Ship got should be
orchestrator, man.
>> Yes.
>> And now that uh Claude the like
Claude pays back, then it makes sense to
use it again.
>> Yeah.
So, what are we going to do?
>> Uh we're going to create loops and
automation.
>> [laughter]
>> On a 5K Mac Mini with 128 GB of RAM.
>> No, 5K M5 laptop.
>> Yeah.
>> Uh that's going to be That's going to be
That's going to be fun.
Uh okay, so
I'm just going to close Okay, where
should we conclude? Yes, so it's time to
go home.
Uh talk what all Claude got. I'm going
to have a look at it. Maybe I can use it
for score survival.
Uh okay, cool. So, are you Are we still
waiting for February 5th?
>> Well, if it comes back, I want to use it
for sure. Yeah. But, I'm also waiting on
the answer from OpenAI.
>> Yes.
>> If they can have a similar model that
will not be banned, they will take a lot
of customers from Anthropic.
>> And it should be cheaper, too.
Cuz they have more compute.
>> So, if they are listening right now,
make the price lower, please.
>> Yes. Price lower, better model,
and [laughter]
and then we can like Yeah, right now I
have two Anthropic subscription. I want
to cancel one so I can buy another one
for Codex and let's go.
Yeah. Because I mean like for Opus 4.6
and 4.7 against 5.5, 5.5 was better.
And then they dropped 4.8 and Ultra
code, and then Codex lost a bit of
steam.
So,
yeah. That's going to be
uh the next few weeks should be
interesting.
Uh Fable 5, I mean, that's it. Is that
the conclusion? I think that
>> Yeah, that's conclusion. We are going to
wait.
>> Let's go.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you so much everyone from the
chat. Uh Michael, uh
yeah, Michael and
uh SG Rack, thank you, and Brian, and uh
Brian, yeah. Okay, cool. Uh for your
comments. Michael, thank you so much for
your time.
>> Thank you, too.
>> And yeah, see you next week.
>> See you.